Something About the Women Radio Show Records MS157
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Something About the Women Radio Show Records
1983 -- 1995
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Something About The Women
MS157
1.7 Linear Feet 1 letter size document box, 1 record carton
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into two series: Playlists and other material; and Tape reels and cassettes.
Scope and Contents
Something About The Women is a women's music radio show aired on the Tufts radio station, WMFO 91.5 FM, in Medford, Massachusetts. It first aired in 1975. This collection contains audiotapes, audiocassettes, 8 tracks, playlists, promotional materials, clippings, and music journals. The bulk of the collection consists of spiral bound playlist notebooks dating from 1979 to 1995, and sound recordings for the show. Sounds recordings include interviews, live performances, and promotional spots from a variety of women performers and activists such as Gloria Steinem, Holly Near, and Terri Gross. Also including in the collection are promotional materials like bumper stickers, relevant music journals, and clippings about the station and performers.
Biographical / Historical
Something About The Women is perhaps the longest running women's music radio show in the United States and is currently produced on a volunteer basis by a collection of five women from the Boston area. The members take turns hosting the show featuring a different voice with a different musical perspective each week.
The show airs on the Tufts radio station, WMFO 91.5 FM, in Medford, Massachusetts. It first aired in 1975 with the goal of featuring music by women artists largely ignored by commercial radio. The music spans all genres, from folk and rock to jazz and world music. The show has now run for 34 years, making it possibly the longest running show on WMFO. It continues to feature an expansive collection of women artists.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection contains some restricted material. Restrictions related to specific material are listed in the detailed contents list. This collection may require review before it is available for use. Please contact DCA for further details.
Something about the women (Radio program); WMFO (Radio station: Medford, Mass.) -- Archives; Women's music; Media and broadcast history; Greater Boston arts
- Playlists and other materials, 1983 -- 1995; 1984 -- 1995; MS157.001; 0.5 Linear Feet
  Scope and Contents
  The series contains playlists and miscellaneous materials from Something About The Women, dating from 1983-1995. The playlists are arranged chronologically starting in 1984 and ending in 1992. The additional material are arranged alphabetically in folders based on format. Dating from 1983 to 1995, the material includes bumper stickers, newspaper clippings, one inventory, and magazines.
  Arrangement
  The series is arranged chronologically for play lists, followed by the additional material.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Open for research.
  - Playlists, 1984 -- 1985; MS157.001.001.00001 (Box 1)
  - Playlists, 1985; MS157.001.001.00002 (Box 1)
  - Playlists, 1989; MS157.001.001.00003 (Box 1)
  - Playlists, 1989 -- 1990; MS157.001.001.00004 (Box 1)
  - Playlists, 1990; MS157.001.001.00005 (Box 1)
  - Playlists, 1992; MS157.001.001.00006 (Box 1)
  - Playlists, 1992 -- 1993; MS157.001.001.00007 (Box 1)
  - Top Music Lists, 1991 -- 1992; MS157.001.001.00008 (Box 1)
  - Playlists, 1993 -- 1994; MS157.001.001.00009 (Box 1)
  - Playlists, 1994 -- 1995; MS157.001.001.00010 (Box 1)
  - Bumper Stickers for 15th anniversary of 'Something About The Women' and for general promotion, 1990; MS157.001.001.00011 (Box 1)
    Date is approximate.
  - File Cabinet Inventory, 1986; MS157.001.001.00012 (Box 1)
  - Hot Wire Journal, 1989-01; MS157.001.001.00013 (Box 1)
  - Hot Wire Journal, 1989-09; MS157.001.001.00014 (Box 1)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1983 -- 1985; MS157.001.001.00015 (Box 1)
- Additional accessions, MS157.002; 3.6 Linear Feet
  - Something About The Women - Tapes and Materials, MS157.001.GB (Box 1)
    Contains open reel-to-reel tapes of interviews, live performances, radio identification, and promotional pieces.
  - Something About The Women - Tapes and Materials, MS157.002.GB (Box 2)
  - Something About The Women, MS157.003.GB (Box 3)
    Former barcode 39090015027284g